<item>
	<title>Post Processed Webskin Magic</title>
	<link>http://farcry.posterous.com/167905337</link>
	<pubDate>Thu Nov 08 19:56:00 -0800 2012</pubDate>
	
	<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geoff Bowers]]></dc:creator>
	
	

	<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

	<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://farcry.posterous.com/167905337</guid>
	<description></description>
	<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ever wanted to just add a link to a YouTube or Vimeo video in your content and have the system convert it to the right embed code? How about a Tweet, or a Gist? &nbsp;If the embed changes (or your design changes!) how cool would it be to just update a central location and have all your embeds update?</p>
<p>Oh, and ever tried to man handle a large embed in a rich text editor like tinyMCE? &nbsp;It can be more than a bit messy.</p>
<p>One seriously cool solution is to post-process your content. Have contributors add URLs into their content and then let the view automatically determine what the right embed should be.</p>
<p>Great news!</p>
<p>As of 6.2.3. Post processing can be added to a webskin using the "postprocess", and those transformations will be applied before the webskin is cached:</p>
<p><code>&lt;!--- @@postprocess: youtube(width=720,height=405);gist ---&gt;</code></p>
<p>This can be applied more selectively with a function or a tag:</p>
<p><code>&lt;cfset result = application.fc.lib.postprocess.apply(stObj.body,"youtube(width=720,height=405);gist")&gt;


&lt;skin:postprocess functions="youtube(width=720,height=405);gist"&gt;#stObj.body#&lt;/skin:postprocess&gt;</code></p>
<p>The function strings must be a semi-colon (;) separated list of functions in the form:</p>
<p><code>[libraryname.]function[(arg1=val1,arg2=val2)]</code></p>
<p>With:</p>
<ul>
<li>an optional library name (this is the name of a component in the lib package in core, your project, or any plugin)</li>
<li>optional arguments (must be named)</li>
</ul>
<p>These functions have been included in core by default:</p>
<ul>
<li>youtube([width],[height])</li>
<li>vimeo([width],[height])</li>
<li>gist</li>
<li>twitter</li>
<li>removewhitespace</li>
</ul>
<p>Enjoy!</p>]]></content:encoded>
	<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[Ever wanted to just add a link to a YouTube or Vimeo video in your content and have the system convert it to the right embed code? How about a Tweet, or a Gist? If the embed changes (or your design changes!) how cool would it be to just update a c...]]></excerpt:encoded>	

	<wp:post_date>Thu Nov 08 19:56:00 -0800 2012</wp:post_date>
	<wp:post_date_gmt>%= display_date %></wp:post_date_gmt>
	<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
	<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
	<wp:post_name>167905337</wp:post_name>
	<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
	<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
	<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
	<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
	<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
	<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>

	
</item>
